我母亲以前常常这么评价住院医师
My mother used to say this about
学习动手术只需一年
It takes a year to learn how to cut
但学习放弃
It takes a life time
却要花一生
To learn not to
我来了 我在这儿
I'm up, I'm here
怎么了?
What's going on?
杰克逊的血压从昨天开始就
Uh, jackson's B.P., It's a little down
一直在降低 没什么大不了
from yesterday.  No big deal
但如果我们打几个电话  表现得主动积极些
but if we make a few calls, get pushy,
也许能让他排到
maybe we could get him bumped up
移植名单的前几位
a few spots up on the transplant list.
贝利医生  你在凌晨两点半
dr. Baey, you-- you paged me 9-1-1
呼我911紧急
at 2:30 in the morning uh,
就是为了聊天?
to chat?
你想要聊天
Uh, you... like to chat.
-你很健谈  -但不是在凌晨两点半
You're chatty. Not at 2:30 in the morning.
你看  他很年轻 一定在名单的首列
Look, he's young.He--he's near the top of the list.
器官共享网络早晚能
U.N.O.S.Will find him his organs
帮他找到匹配的器官
when they find him his organs.
老天爷知道整晚讨论这个
And god knowthat staying up all night chatting about it
没有任何帮助
is not gonna help.
我可要去睡觉了
I'm gonna go get some sleep.
我建议你也睡觉吧
I suggest you do the same.
他快没时间了
He's running out of time.
所有的病人都这样
They always are.
欢迎光临儿科
Welcome to peds.
外科工具所有的清单中
Of all of the tools on a surgical tray...
精准判断是最难掌控的一项
Sound judgment is the trickiest one to master.
没有这个
And without it,
我们都是带着手术刀屁颠屁颠乱跑的小屁孩
We're all just toddlers running around with 10-blades.
我叫他们不要吵醒你
Oh, I asked them not to wake you.
我说过 无论如何 都能等到早上
I said, "whatever it is, it can wait till morning.
谢博德医生需要睡美容觉
Dr. shepherd needs his beauty sleep."
你最近的脑CT显示脑挫裂伤势
Your latest head c.t. shows that the brain contusions
正在扩大
Are expanding.
我得立即送你去手术室
I'm gonna get you into the o.r. right away.
这个脑伤 会要了我的命吗？
This--this brain thing, it--it could kill me?
如果不立即处理  就会
If we don't treat it, yes.
- 这有什么好笑的? -抱歉
You find that funny? I'm sorry.
我五天后就会被处决
It's just that they're gonna execute me in five days.
五天
Five days.
不如就听天由命算了  怎样?
Might as well take my chances with this brain thing, right?
登先生
Mr. dunn--
你得承认 死在这儿还不赖
You gotta admit, it's a nice way to go--
有很多漂亮姑娘
Plenty of attractive females...
吃不完的果冻
All the jell-o I could want.
你有没有尝过草莓味的? 简直可以颠覆你的人生观
Have you tried the strawberry? it'll change your life.
你拒绝做手术?
You're refusing surgery?
横也是死
Either way,
竖也是死  谢博德医生
I'm going to die, dr. shepherd.
倒不如你看着我死
Might as well do it on your watch.
你为什么要住在Meredith的阁楼里?
Why do you have to live in meredith's attic?
我怎么偷偷溜下去
How am I supposed to sneak out of here
不惊动楼下的人呢?
With that frat party going on downstairs?
-那些孩子怎么就不睡呢? -他们在给谢博得医生的妈妈打扫房子
Don't you kids ever sleep? they're cleaning the house for dr.
谢博得的妈妈
Shepherd's mother.
谢博得夫人来了?
Mrs. shepherd's coming?
来西雅图?
To seattle?
-所以?  那个女人把我养大了
So? so that woman practically raised me,
教会我怎样判断是非
Taught me right from wrong,
如果她发现我
And if she found out that I was...
和你搞在一起
With you, that we were...
你是梅丽迪斯的妹妹
You're meredith grey's little sister.
是颗禁果  你才25
You are forbidden fruit. you are 25.
乳臭未干
You're a fetus.
24岁 我三年级跳级了
24. I skipped third grade.
我觉得很龌龊
I feel dirty.
赌10块 她5分钟内崩溃
10 bucks says she tanks in the first 5 minutes.
我对死神有信心 肯定会留下个好印象
I have faith in death. she'll make a good impression.
她揣着那瓶龙舌根 就像是件救生衣
She's holding that bottle of tequila like it's a life vest.
小梅 别听他们的 她会爱你的
Mer, don't listen to them. she's gonna love you.
不 妈妈们不喜欢我
No. mothers don't love me.
妈妈们喜欢聪明活泼的
Mothers like bright and bubbly and happy and...
伊兹 妈妈们爱伊兹
Izzie. mothers love izzie.
是的  她们喜欢伊兹
They do. mothers do love izzie.
我妈妈会喜欢你的
My mother would've loved you.
我把龙舌兰酒藏起来了
Uh, I stashed all the tequila,
也把避孕套从甜点罐里拿出来了
Took the condoms out of the cookie jar.
还用外科年鉴换掉了
I also replaced all your trashy magazines
垃圾杂志   好了吗?
With back issues of the "annals of surgery, " okay?
这里是不是有点霉味?
Does it smell musty in here?
我妈的房子一股薄荷味
My mom's house smells like peppermint.
- 所以很舒适吧  - 我家就不舒适?
It's so homey. my house isn't homey?
- 我很惬意  - 我在一糜烂的地方长大  像宫殿
I feel at home. I was raised in a hellhole. this place is a palace.
-我的家怎么就不舒适了  乔治  -我说不上来 就是感觉
Why isn't my houseomey, george? I can't explain it. it's just a feeling.
伊兹不会改改感觉 她吓坏了
Well, izzie can't fix a feeling. she is freaking out, people.
跟她说点我能干的  跟她说点我能干的
Just tell her something I can fix. rebecca peed on that couch cushion.
丽贝卡在沙发垫子上小便过
I've been sleeping there for weeks.
谢谢你 爱厉克斯 你是个好伙计
Thanks, alex. you're... a good friend.
不客气 继续喝你的
You're welcome. keep drinking.
马克 你在这儿
Mark. hey, there you are.
-要喝点什么不? -现在是凌晨4点
Want to get a drink? it's 4:00 in the morning.
没错 我也许先应该打个电话
Yeah, you're right. I probably, uh, shoulda called first.
我听说你妈妈要来 美好时光哦
Hey, I hear your mom's coming into town. good times.
你会好的
You'll be fine.
尽量少说话
Just keep the talking to a minimum. short.
安静有内涵的梅丽迪斯
Short little nuggets of meredith--
会是大众都喜欢的模样
That's all anyone really needs.
如果你一下子应付不来 那就笑一下
And if you start to get stuck, just smile.
你的笑容还不赖啦
You have a really great smile.
是哭笑不得吧...
Ooh. that's just scary.
小梅 你确定想要这个发型吗?
Um, mer, are you sure you want to wear your hair like that?
你这个马尾辫太高调了
You're wearing an alarmingly high ponytail.
你母亲要来了
Your mother is coming.
登先生
Mr. dunn,
你头部的肿块长得很快
The swelling in your brain is increasing rapidly.
手术做得越迟 情况越糟
The longer we wait to operate, the worse it gets.
很好 你们一伙人走开吧
Excellent. go, team.
我强烈建议你再考虑下动手术
I strongly suggest you reconsider surgery.
你见过一级戒备的监狱里面吗?
Have you ever seen the inside of a maximum security prison? mnh-mnh.
相信我 就算死也要死在这
Believe me, if you have to die, this is the place to do it,
有人陪着我
In good company.
你俩要密切关注登先生的颅内压
You two will vigilantly monitor mr. dunn's elevating i.c.p.s.
你要每小时做次脑部检查
You will do hourly neuro exams.
等他失去意识  那就不是他能决定了
When he goes unconscious, which he will,
-就赶紧送他去手术室 -你不能这样做
We'll rush him to surgery. you can't do that.
-他能这样吗? -当你失去意识
Can--can--can he do that? when you're unconscious
不能再做出正确的医疗决定时
And can no longer make sound medical decisions,
只需要2名医生同意就能治疗你
A 2-doctor consent is all that's needed to treat you.
老天啊 5天后我就要归西了
For god sake, I'm gonna be dead as a doornail in five days.
格蕾医生 你是个讲道理的...
Dr. grey, you're a reasonable--
-就这么定了 -一台-破电视 你还修什么?
We're done here. would you fix a broken television
反正都要扔了
Before you throw it out?
他说得有道理
He's got a point.
他要钻政策的空子
He's trying to cheat the system,
我们不能让他这样做
And we're not gonna let him do it.
怎么了?
What's the problem?
我做了个小手术 然后有点小感染
I have a little infection from a little surgery I had done.
在香港做的
Yeah, in hong kong.
我的疯子老哥
My crazy-ass brother
在香港做的这个
Went and got crazy-ass elective surgery
疯子手术
In hong kong.
谁会做这个?
Who does that?
矮人们  绝望的矮人们
Short people. desperate short people.
我把腿拉长了
I had my legs lengthened.
-我在这找不到医生做这个 -这是不是很野蛮?
I couldn't find a surgeon who would do it here. look, it's barbaric, okay?
他们先打断他的腿 再用一些刑具一样的东西
They--they broke his legs and they hooked him up
把腿接起来
To some sort of medieval torture device.
就是为了把骨头分离
Yeah, that's to pull the bones apart.
那是增高的过程 它很有争议性
That's the lengthening process. it's a controversial procedure.
我自己不会做这种手术 能让我看一下吗
I don't perform it myself. could I take a look?
他们说着能足足增高2英寸
They said it'd give me 2 whole inches.
器官共享网络有消息吗?
Any word from u.n.o.s.?
还没有
Not yet.
克莱夫医生一直在跟他们联络
Dr. karev is staying in constant contact with them.
我们还得等多久?
How much longer will we have to wait?
很难找到匹配的肝肠吗?
Are--are livers and intestines hard to find?
杰克逊的血型是O型阳性
Well, jackson's blood type is o-positive.
应该容易有匹配
It shouldn't be too difficult to match.
但是他有输血
But he's had blood transfusions,
意味着可能有额外抗体
Which means there could be extra antibodies
这下就很难匹配了
That are hard to match,
我们要有耐心 木兰达
So we need to be patient, melinda.
同时 我还要
In the meantime, um, I need
做点检查 看看杰克逊的电解质
To run some tests on jackson to check his electrolytes.
我们会尽力来
We're gonna do everything we can
帮助你儿子的 普莱斯科特夫人
To help your son, mrs. prescott.
我们都会尽力的
All of us.
你很古怪
You. you're squirrelly.
-什么?  -我不信任你
I'm sorry? I don't trust you.
我不放心你在这家医院工作
I don't trust you in this hospital
显然我不放心把跟了我三年的
And I certainly don't trust you with my patient of three years
-重要病人交给你 -我
Who's extremely important. i--
如果想继续这个病例
Zz. if you want to stay on this case,
就别插手 我说什么你做什么
You will stay out of my way, you will do what I tell you,
如果你对我的病人有任何意见观点
And if you have something to say to or about my patient,
都得先乖乖举手 然后通过我的同意
You will raise your hand and wait to be called on.
你开玩笑的吧
You--you've got to be kidding me.
说
Yes.
你开玩笑的吧
This is a joke, right?
我的样子像在说笑吗?
Do I look like I'm laughing?
你在生气
You're upset.
我从来不生病人的气
I don't get upset with patients.
你觉得我杀了那些女人很恐怖
You're mad at me for killing those women.
我知道的
I get that.
如果你知道我儿时被虐待
Would you feel differently if you knew
会对我有所改观吗?
That I was beaten as a child?
每天如此
Every day.
你知道我怎么学会阅读的吗?
It's how I learned to read.
我躲在水槽下
I-i used to hide under the sink
念洗涤剂包装上的文字
And sound out the letters on the detergent box.
真的吗?
Is that true?
这样让你好受些吗?
Did it make you feel better?
只要能让你安心入眠 格蕾医生
Whatever helps you sleep at night, dr. grey.
你做了什么坏事吗?
Did you do something bad?
交通违章
Traffic violation.
你怎么了 小子?
What's wrong with you, kid?
我需要移植肠和肝脏
I need a new liver and a new intestine.
真的? 想要我的吗?
Yeah? you want mine?
你在北站吗?
Are you in the north terminal?
她应该到那儿了
Well, that's where she's supposed to be.
不不 哪儿也别去 就在那等
No, no, do-don't go anywhere. just wait.
不用了 我见到她了
Never mind. I found her.
其实在机场有专门的车接你的
You know, there's a town car waiting for you at the airport.
犯不着这么豪华的车 我坐巴士来
I don't need a fancy car. I just hopped on the bus.
-帮你省点钱 -所以这次旅途
Saved you some money. so this cruise...
你是恰好路过这里西雅图吗?
You just happened to have a layover in seattle?
是啊 我一直想来瞧瞧太空塔
Well, I've always wanted to check out the space needle.
我知道从塔顶可以看到瑞尼尔山
I understand you can see mount rainer from the top.
是吗? 还有什么是你想瞧瞧的呢?
Oh, really? anything else you want to check out?
你打算带我去看什么呢?
You gonna take me or not? I got back-to-back surgeries, ma.
你应该先跟我说医生
You gotta give me a little more notice. yeah, yeah.
我生了5个医生啦 我知道规矩
I gave birth to five doctors. I know the drill.
我等着好了 或者见见你的同事
I can wait, maybe meet your colleagues.
那是马克斯隆吗?
Is that mark sloan?
没错
Yeah.
马克斯隆
Mark sloan.
谢博德夫人 您看上去不错
Oh, mrs. shepherd. you look great.
要命 等一下见吧
Oh, damn. catch up later?
哦 来得正好  妈妈  这是梅丽迪斯
Uh, oh, perfect timing. um, mom, this is meredith.
梅丽迪斯  终于看到本人了
Meredith, finally.
我儿子像小狗藏骨头一样
Hi. my son has been acting like a dog with his favorite bone,
把你藏起来
Hiding you away.
我想和你一起吃午饭可以不
I hope you're free for lunch.
我等不及要好好了解你了
I can't wait to dive in and find out all about you.
梅丽看上去怪怪的 你觉得怪不
Mer looks weird. does she look weird to you?
他看上去都快尿裤子了
She looks like she's gonna pee her pants. oh, crap.
-我给她灌太多水了 -会见家庭成员真的很麻烦
I made her hydrate. meeting the family always blows.
我永远不会要你见的
I'd never make you do that.
我也不会 跟已故的人交往的好处之一哦
Me, either. one of the many perks of dating a dead guy. mm.
那个和梅丽迪斯拥抱的人是谁?
Who's that lady touching meredith?
德瑞克的母亲
Derek's mom.
所以她看起来怪怪的
Oh, that's why she looks so weird.
她没有很怪 我都帮她想到安排好了
She does not look weird, okay? I've got it under control.
她表现的不错
Mer is doing... great.
看上去要尿裤子
Looks like she's gonna pee.
杨医生 能帮我检查一下术后病患吗?
Dr. yang, you mind checking on some of my post-ops?
急诊室人满为患
E.r. is swamped with traumas.
还有 你愿意和我约会吗?
Also, would you like to go on a date with me?
什么?
I'm sorry?
约会
A date.
你说不要对你忽冷忽热
You said not to play hot and cold with you,
那么 我8点来接你?
So, um, I'll pick you up around 8:00?
哦 确保给2212床的肯纳灌肠剂
Oh, and make sure mr. kenner in room 2-2-1-2 gets that enema.
他便秘好几天了
He's been holding on to it for days.
好的
Okay.
这才怪怪的吧
'cause that wasn't weird.
看到了吧 跟已故者交往的另一个好处
See, another perk of dating a dead guy--
没有糟糕的约会
No awkward dates.
2比1 谁比较好?
2-to-1, but who's counting?
我为什么不能接受那个好心人的器官?
Why can't I have that nice man's organs?
他愿意给我
He offered.
就像在学校里
You know how in school,
有些规矩必须要遵守
There are rules you have to follow?
在这儿也是一样
Well, the same goes for here.
我们不守规则的话
We have to follow the rules,
就会有大麻烦
Or else we get in big trouble.
那个人要给你器官
And what that man offered you...
是绝对违反规定的
Was definitely against the rules.
她又在和保险公司的人争执
She's fighting with the insurance people again.
你不用操心那些事情
You're not supposed to worry about stuff like that.
跟她说点好话
Tell her something good today,
就算没有好事
Even if nothing good happens,
她需要好话
She needs good news.
我身体里装满了健康的器官
I've got a body full of-- of high-quality parts here.
还有3天时间
3-day liquidation sale.
每样都拿走
Everything must go.
就算我们可以 也得和他的匹配
Even if we could do it, you have to be a match for him,
也就是说要拿你的血和他的交叉配型
Which means we'd have to crossmatch your blood with his.
幸运的是我们在一个医院
Good thing we're both in a hospital then.
让我死前救一条生命吧
Let--let me save a life before I go.
这是我最后能做的事情了
It's the--it's the least I can do.
你指望我相信
So you really expect me to believe
你这么做是为了一个孩子?
That you want to do this for a kid?
只要能让你安心入眠  格蕾医生
Whatever helps you sleep at night, dr. grey.
感染已经深入骨头了
The infection's made its way deep into the bone,
所以要把钢钎从你的腿里取出...
So we're gonna have to take the rods out of your legs...
并且清理掉坏死 受感染的表皮和骨头
And clean out the dead, infected skin and bone.
你是说那两英寸没了?
You mean I won't get my 2 inches?
-痛苦都白费了? -茹本先生 鉴于你的情况
All that pain for nothing? mr. ruben, at this point,
你能保住双腿就算走运了
You're lucky to keep your legs at all.
你说得到容易
Yeah, that's easy for you to say.
-你多高? 1米7还是1米8? -别跟医生争 切克
What are you, 5'10", 5'11"? leave the doctors, alone, chuck.
他们是为了你好
They're just trying to help.
闭嘴 盖雷 你都185了
Oh, shut up, gary. you are over 6 feet tall.
你了解每个人都低头
Do you have any idea what it's like
俯瞰你的滋味吗？
To have everybody you know literally look down on you?
你能够了解
Or how humiliating it is
拿不到货架上的东西
To have to ask for help from a teenager at the grocery store
只好请小孩子帮忙的感受吗?
'cause you can't reach the top shelf?
过去的6个月中我的谈了两次恋爱
I've gone on two dates in the last six months,
都是在网上认识的女人
Both with women I met over the internet,
都不愿意见我第二面
And hey, no one wants to see me again
没人喜欢跟矮子约会
Because no one wants to date the short guy.
-切克 -我要保住这2英寸 盖雷
Chuck-- I wanted those 2 inches, gary.
我真的很想保住它们
I wanted them so bad.
那可是2英寸啊
It's 2 inches.
可160和165有差吗?
I mean, wh-what's the difference between 5'3" and 5'5"?
165就能大声说出来啦
5'5" you can say out loud.
我列了张
Okay, I made a list
全国最好的儿科专家的清单
Of the best pediatric g.i.s in the country.
我觉得 凭咱们两个
I figure, between the two of us,
可以有能力找来其中一个
We can get one of these guys to come down
来帮这孩子动系统处理性手术
And do a tips procedure on him.
帮一个需要肝脏移植的孩子做这种手术?
Doing a tips on a kid who needs a new liver?
没错  这和在枪伤上贴邦迪没什么区别
Yeah. that--that's like putting a band-aid on a bullet wound.
-那你有更好的建议吗?  -有 等器官共享网络
Well, you have a better idea? I do. waiting for u.n.o.s.
相信系统
Trusting the process.
那你为什么不能那么做呢?
W-why can't you do that?
这孩子每况愈下 我真的等不下去了
Because I'm tired of waiting while this kid is getting worse.
杰克逊厌倦了  他妈妈也是
Jackson's tired. his mother is, too.
只有你一个乐滋滋的坐着
The only one who's happy to sit on her ass
什么努力也不做!
And twiddle her thumbs and wait is you! whoa.
我受够你了  我忍你很久了
I have been patient with you. I have been nice.
但我受不了了
But I am really over you... hey.
-一直给我发号施令  -总有人要
Constantly telling me how to do my job. okay, somebody has to--
贝利医生  这家医院还有20个孩子等着我治疗
Dr. bailey. I've got 20 other kids in this hospital--
-我说的只是这一个孩子   -给我闭嘴!
I'm concerned about this one child-- shut up!
别争了  别争了 给我关掉 我们有器官了
Respectfully, all right? respectfully, shut up.
真希望器官送过来
I wish you could get organs delivered
而不是我们去取  对吧?
Instead of having to go pick them up, you know?
我讨厌坐飞机
I hate flying.
我总觉得坐飞机很容易死掉
I always feel much closer to death on a plane
比在手术室更危险
Than in the o.r.
你呢?
Don't you?
现在是这么认为
I do now.
我见过伊兹了
I met izzie the other day.
她是个美人
She's very pretty.
你觉得就是她了对不?
So you--you think she's the one?
我不知道
I-i don't know.
我是说我们都老大不小了  对吧
Well, I mean, we're at that age, right?
结婚 生育什么的计划
Marriage, babies... that the plan?
我不知道!
I don't know!
抱歉 我可没什么计划  行不?
I'm sorry. i-i don't make plans, okay?
有个未来的确不错  如果没有 那随便好了
If there's a future there, great. if not, whatever.
我很快就会好了  我一直很坚强好不好
I'll get over it. I always do. okay?
好吧
Okay.
你的约会很不错
I think it's nice. your date.
你跟那个杀猪狂
I think you and the pig murderer
还真是天生一对
Make a really good couple.
约会时你俩要干什么
Okay. what are you gonna do on your date?
-说什么呢? -关你什么事呢
What are you gonna talk about? why do you care?
就是  关你什么事呢
Yeah, why do you care?
初次约会就只有一次
You only get to do a first date once.
应该有趣并且火辣
It should be... fun and sexy and...
问一些有价值的问题
Oh, ask really good questions.
问他最初为什么想要救死扶伤
Ask him why he first decided he wanted to save lives.
问他做得最好的一个手术是什么
Ooh, ask him what his best surgery ever was. I know how to go on a date.
梅丽迪斯为什么要吃焖烧牛肉?
Why is meredith eating pot roast?
在未来婆婆面前表演呢
It's a show lunch for the mommy.
她紧张极了 还有马尾辫 会爆开的
She's freaking out. that ponytail? it's gonna blow.
德瑞克跟我我说你在西雅图长大
Derek tells me you--you, uh, grew up right here in seattle.
那你父母亲也是...
Are your parents...
都过世了
Mm. dead.
梅丽的妈妈去年过世的
Mer's mother died last year.
很抱歉  你父亲呢?
Oh. oh, I'm so sorry. and your father?
哦 我要去
Oh. you know, i...
看看病人
Should go check on the patient
那个连环杀手
Who's the serial killer...
他就在医院里
Who's here.
现在可没有杀人
Not killing people,
还不错
So that's good.
我该走了
I should go. yeah.
她不喜欢家庭这个话题
Family isn't her favorite topic, okay?
她真的很不容易
She's had a rough time of it.
我什么也没说啊
I didn't say a word.
我知道你在想什么
I know what you're thinking.
我在想
I was thinking...
要你治疗一个杀人凶手
It must be awful for you...
一定很不舒服
Treating a murderer.
爸爸去世很久了 我没事
Dad died a long time ago. I'm fine.
格蕾 你干什么呢?
Grey, what are you doing?
一起睡就要一起吃 新规矩
If you sleep with me, you lunch with me. new rule.
斯隆医生 你肯和实习生吃午饭?
You let interns sit with you at lunch, dr. sloan?
真酷阿
That is so cool.
跟我换饼干吃吧
Oh, you want to go halfsies with me on that cookie?
那你拿什么跟我换呢?
Uh, what are you gonna trade me for it, huh?
伙计们 这里有卖Tater Tots薯片!
You guys, they have tater tots!
我得走了
I have to go.
马克
Mark.
谢博德夫人
Mrs. shepherd.
你一直在躲我
You've been avoiding me.
- 哪有  -你十岁那年把德瑞克最爱的青蛙
What? no. you have that same guilty look on your face
放进微波炉烤了之后
As you did when you were 10 years old
也是这副内疚的臭表情
And you put derek's favorite frog into the microwave.
我可从来没有按过“开始”键
I never pressed "start."
发生什么了
What's going on?
我跟她睡过了
I'm sleeping with her.
噢  马克!
Oh, mark!
又来了  你怎么敢这样
Not again. how could you?
不 不 不 不是梅丽迪斯  上帝  不是
No, no. no, not meredith. god, no.
梅丽迪斯的小妹妹
Meredith's little sister.
她是哪个人
Which one is she?
喝果汁的那个
The, uh, the... one with the juice box.
我的新器官来了吗?
Are my new organs here yet?
还没有  但要先帮你做术前准备
Mm, not yet. but we're gonna get you all prepped now.
等器官一到 才能马上移植
So that we can put them in as soon as they get here.
等你醒来
When you wake up,
就是拥有新器官和崭新男孩了
You're gonna be a brand-new boy with brand-new parts.
真不敢相信
I can't believe this is it.
我们对于
The thought of us
再也不要三天两头跑医院的愿望
Getting to live our lives outside of this hospital...
别误会 穆兰达 我喜欢跟你说话
Don't get me wrong, miranda. I love our chats.
不过用不着每天见我这张脸了 很高兴吧?
But it'll be nice not to see my face every day?
再高兴不过了
So freakin' nice.
他还是个孩子啊
It's just a kid.
没错 我们这就去取他的器官
Yep. let's go get his organs.
我在做梦
Am I hallucinating,
还是真看到马尾辫了?
Or is that a really high ponytail?
你醒着呢
You're not hallucinating.
但一旦你发生脑疝
But once your brain starts to herniate,
可就说不准了
I can't promise anything.
那么我真的会在这边耗死吗?
So I'm really circling the drain here?
你该用我的器官
You should just take my organs right now,
马上去救那可怜的孩子
Help that poor kid.
他们找到匹配的器官了
Oh, they found him organs.
正飞过去取  他会康复的
They're flying them over right now. he's gonna be fine.
你知道他们可以让你自己选死法吗?
Did you know that they let you choose?
绞刑或注射
Hanging or lethal--
如果可以自己挑选毒药
You get to pick your poison, literally.
你会选哪种?
Which one would you choose?
从医学角度讲
Medically speaking,
哪种...好受些?
Which one's... better?
绞刑导致颈部折断
Well, with hanging, your neck breaks,
切断脊髓
Which severs your spinal cord,
致使你的血压降为零
Which causes your blood pressure to drop to nothing,
你会失去知觉
And you lose consciousness.
几分钟后才真正死去
You don't actually die for several minutes.
如果选择药物注射
And with lethal injection,
之前会先注射麻醉剂
They inject an anesthetic first,
使你睡着
Which puts you to sleep,
然后注射肌肉松弛剂
And then a paralytic,
停止你的呼吸系统
Which stops your diaphragm and your lungs,
最后使用氯化钾停止你的心跳
And then potassium, which stops your heart.
这...
Was, um...
我是匹配者吗?
Was I a match?
你是
Yes, you were.
我能帮你什么吗?
Can I help you with something?
你在找谢博德医生?
Were you looking for dr. shep--
你是一个好女孩吗?
Are you a good girl?
我 什么
I--what?
一个好女孩
A good girl.
不需要完美  我是说  基本上
I don't mean perfect. I mean... relatively speaking.
-你是吗? -是的
Are you? yes.
你曾经有过多少个性伴侣
How many sexual partners have you had?
我不会以此判断你的
I won't judge.
6个 不 7个
Um... six. no, s-seven.
好像是6个 好像是7个
K-kinda six. but kinda seven.
-犯罪记录呢? -超速罚单
Criminal record? speeding ticket.
-超了多少? -12英里
How fast? 12 miles over.
好快
That's fast.
不  是太快了
Well, it wasn't too-- it wa--it was way too fast.
但我是在下坡  我  我
But I was--i was downhill and I was--i was--
只是滑行 女士
I was coasting, ma'am.
有点冒昧  不过能告诉我
Now I don't suppose you can tell me...
礼品商店在哪吗?
Where the gift shop is?
东楼 1层
First floor, east wing.
这像是布丁
It's like pudding in here.
所以我才不做这种手术
This is exactly why I don't do this procedure.
我是说  带着断腿在一起生活这么多个月
I mean, you're living with broken legs for months.
你忍受着非人的折磨  就为了几英寸
You're in excruciating pain. god, all for a few inches.
着就叫做痛并快乐着
Pain and agony for a little bit of pleasure.
了解
I get it.
如果真的那么糟糕  你为什么还和他做
If it's that bad, why don't you just stop sleep--
做你正在做的事情?
Doing what you're doing?
因为我做的时候并没有感觉很糟
Because it doesn't feel bad when I'm... doing it.
很好  很棒
It's good. it's great.
如果你不害怕伤痕累累
And maybe if you weren't so scared of getting burned,
你也有感同身受的机会
You'd feel the same.
你知道吗? 我总是觉得自己高高在上
You know, I used to walk tall around here.
一直这样子
I used to walk tall.
直到乔治出现
Then... came george.
他至少把我往下挪了1英寸
He took off at least an inch.
然后挨瑞卡离开了我  又往下挪了些
Then erica went and left me. that shaved off a few more.
我越来越往下
I got shorter.
所有的这些屈辱  让我越来越矮
All that humiliation, it makes you shorter.
是的  我害怕受到伤害
So, yeah, I am scared of getting hurt
因为再经历一次情感伤害
Because one more personal disaster right now
会让我一直矮到膝盖
Would cut me off at the knees.
所以 情人节呢?
So, uh, valentine's day?
个人认为 珠宝永远是正确的选择
Personally, I mean, I think you can't go wrong with jewelry.
如果需要 我可以推荐一些本地的
If you want, I can recommend some local plac--
-你是怎么回事?  -什么?
What is wrong with you? what?
我们刚从一个孩子那
We just took a liver and an intestine
取走了肝脏和小肠  一个孩子死了
From a little kid-- a dead little kid--
你却漠不关心
And you don't even care.
你大谈彩虹啊恋爱啊这些废话
You're talking about rainbows and relationships and crap.
你到底怎么了?
What the hell is wrong with you?
你觉得我不知道
You don't think that I know
他们刚为一个孩子做了器官切除?
That they just pulled the plug on a kid?
你觉得我对此木讷吗?
You don't think I get that?
你觉得我会不知道
You don't think I know
他们会把他放入一个很小很小的棺材?
About the tiny, tiny coffin they're gonna stick him in?
我知道那些小棺材
I know about the tiny coffins.
我在梦里经常见到它们
I see them all the time, in my sleep.
所以如果不介意
So if you don't mind,
我还是要继续谈论恋爱啊
I'm gonna keep talking relationships
彩虹什么的废话
And rainbows and crap,
我还要做明天的日程规划
And I'm gonna make plans for tomorrow,
因为这是你的工作  克莱夫
Because that's what you do, karev.
你作计划?
You make plans.
不得不作
You have to.
抛开那些小棺材
You turn your back on the tiny coffins
朝前看
And you face forward...
去关注下一个孩子
To the next kid.
-那个死刑犯怎么样了?  -我要疯了
So how's our death row guy? oh, he's pissing me off.
他现在脑袋就像开花了
He has blossoming brain contusions now,
却拒绝做手术
And he's refusing surgery.
他认为这能使他免于行刑?
He thinks that's gonna get him a stay of execution?
不 他只是想死在这
No, he'd just like to die here.
他要自己掌控  自己选择
He wants to control it, wants to choose.
我越俎代庖帮你的侄子们买了小熊
I went a little overboard buying bears for your nieces.
妈妈  这是欧文亨特少校
Mom, this is major owen hunt.
少校?  我做了25年海军护士
Major? I was navy nurse for 25 years.
-你的驻扎地在哪里 Hunt少校?  -在最需要的地方 伊拉克
Where were you stationed, major hunt? in the thick of it, in iraq.
欢迎回来  你一定有很多经历
Welcome home. you must have stories.
都不值一提  女士
Not any worth telling, ma'am.
我做好了术后护理
I finished your post-ops.
谢谢  杨医生
Thank you, dr. yang.
你做过的最成功的手术是什么?
So what was your best surgery ever?
什么?
What?
没什么  我...真蠢
Nothing. i, uh... stupid
-下腔静脉好了  -脉络膜看上去很好
Finishing the vena cava. anastamosis looks good.
现在只剩松开钳子了
Nol all that's left is to release the clamps.
你该享受这一时刻 穆兰达
U you should ohoe ho, rsrandra
他是你的病人
He is your patient
谢谢你 罗宾医生
thank you dr.robbin
我有话要说
Call on me!
十二指肠上面有个斑点
There's a spot on the duodenum.
那是什么东西?
What the hell is that?
我觉得不舒服
I don't feel too good.
颅内压太高了  我们不能等了
I.c.p. is critical. we can't wait anymore.
-必须送他去手术室  -不 不
We have to get him down to the o.r. no. no.
我们得送你去做手术
We have to get you to surgery.
我不怕死
I'm not scared of dying.
我只是不愿意被绑在手术台上
I just don't want to do it strapped down to a table
像个畜牲一样
Like some a-animal.
求求你  求求你  求求你了  格蕾医生
Please, please... please, dr. grey...
让我死吧
Let me go.
注射肌肉松弛剂
Push the parytics.
开始移床
Okay, start bagging him.
插管 送他去手术室
Intubate and get him into the o.r.
我需要另一个医生的签字
I need another doctor's signature...
-来同意手术  -好了 签吧
Consent to operate... all right, sign.
签了这表格
Sign the form.
梅丽迪斯  签名
Meredith, sign the form.
Meredith! sign the form.
杨  你来做手术
Yang, you're scrubbing in.
他一直在凝血  不停的
He's clotting and clotting and clotting.
有什么原因吗? 这不可能吧
Is there a source? this can't be happening.
这不会吧  发生在这个小男孩身上
This just cannot be happening, not to this little boy.
别这样  别这样  这些器官衰竭了
This is not happening. this is not happening. these organs are dead, dr.
贝利医生
Bailey.
它们让他更严重了
They're making him sicker.
-把它们留在里面只有更多的坏处 -老大 也许
Keeping them in is doing him more harm than good. sir, maybe if--
-你把它们留着他会死的  -如果拿走他会死的 老大
He will die if you leave them in. he'll die if we take them out, sir.
也许可以试试静脉分流
Maybe we could try a portacaval shunt.
这样能够维持循环系统 绕开肝脏
It'll keep the circulation going and bypass the liver.
这只是暂时性的措施  有人有更好的主意吗?
That's just a temporary fix. anybody got any better ideas?
看来我们别无选择了 贝利医生
Then I don't see what choice we have, dr. bailey.
我们有多少时间去找新的器官?
How much time do we have to find him new organs?
24小时
24 hours.
这里也再多包扎点
Get some more laps in there, too.
我们要把这块骨头
We're gonna put this piece of skull
植入登的腹部
In mr. dunn's abdomen.
为什么?
Why?
使得颅内高压缓解
To allow the swelling in the brain to resolve.
腹部的循环
The circulation of the abdomen
能够保存好头骨的骨髓
Preserves the bone marrow of the skull piece.
很好
Very good.
谢谢能让我做手术
Thanks for letting me scrub in.
我们终于有达成一致的时候了
I guess we finally see eye to eye on something.
我们能找出血凝的原因吗?
Are we ever gonna find out why it clotted off?
有时候身体的零件就这么坏了
Sometimes the body-- the pieces just break.
跟我一样
I'm like that.
是吗?  就这样莫名其妙的死掉?
Yeah? you dying for no good reason?
不 我的生活支离破碎
No, my life is in pieces...
一直是
All the time.
一片片破裂
And... and they just keep breaking.
刚修好这片  那片又破了
And as soon as I fix one, another one goes down.
听我说  我没有来这里把你惹毛
Listen, I'm not trying to piss you off by being here.
我只想要让我的生活变得完整
I'm just trying to... keep it together,
就像拼图
You know, piece by piece.
那个马尾辫
That ponytail...
荒唐极了
Looks ridiculous.
她是个可爱的女孩
She's a lovely girl.
一个很难解读的可爱女孩
A lovely girl who's off-limits.
乱讲  问题不在她这边  而在你这边
Baloney. she isn't the problem. you are.
你太看低自己了  马克斯隆
You have very low expectations for yourself, mark sloan.
从你小时候起  你就这样
Since you were a little boy, you always have.
-是时候拾起信心了  -她才24
And it's time to raise them. she's 24.
你的情商只有一个15岁的小屁孩那么多
You have the emotional maturity of a horny 15 year old.
你需要年轻女孩
You need young.
为了保住你的腿 我们不得不磨掉
So we had to shave off about a quarter-inch of leg bone
你0.25英寸的腿骨
In order to save the legs.
你是说我会更矮?
You mean I'm shorter?
再矮一四分之一英寸?
I'm a quarter of an inch shorter?!
只不过四分之一英寸  没什么大不了的
It's a quarter-inch. it's not a big deal.
是吗?
Yeah?
我连160也没了
I am under 5'3".
158厘米吗?
I am 5'2 and 3/4s?
噢  不  也许还能
Oh, no, but, hey, uh, maybe I could still
勉强挤进
Just squeeze over
-娱乐场所的身高限制线  -噢!
That height requirement at the amusement park. oh!
知道我为什么没进大学篮球队吗
Do you know why I never played varsity basketball?
因为队里不需要你?
'cause you didn't make the team?
不 不 不  我根本没去尝试
No, no, no. i-i didn't try out for the team
我不想让你觉得自己太矮
Because I didn't want to make you feel bad
所以不能打球
For being too short to play. wh--
至今  我仍然很苦恼
Even now, if I have a bad day,
我甚至不能跟我哥哥说这个事情
I can't even talk to my own brother about it,
因为这样你也许正难过  觉得自己矮
Because maybe you had a bad day, and you're short.
就算罗丽离开了我 我都不能觉得伤心
I couldn't even get depressed about lori leaving me
因为你根本没有女朋友 因为你矮
Because you don't have a girlfriend and you're short!
还有  你没有女朋友的原因
And by the way, the reason you don't have a girlfriend--
并不是因为你矮
It's not because you're short.
因为你一天到晚都在唠叨自己矮
It's because all you ever do is talk about being short!
天知道你觉得自己有多矮  伙计
No one knows how short you are except for you, dude
谁要理你呢
No one cares.
我很混账  是不是?
I'm an ass, aren't i?
没错
Yeah.
你是个矮子
And you're short.
晚安  谢博德夫人  很高兴见到你
Good night, mrs. shepherd. nice to meet you.
亨特上校  睡得好吗?
Major hunt, how have you been sleeping?
你说什么?
I'm sorry?
我睡不着时 就吃缬草根
When I can't sleep, I use valerian root.
我知道你们医生觉得草药没什么用
I know you doctors don't think much of herbs,
但我觉得挺管用的
But I find it helps.
回来之后.
Have you been sleeping.
你睡着过吗?
Since you came back?
我很好 女士
I'm fine, ma'am.
我睡得很好
I... sleep just fine.
晚安
Good night.
头还疼吗? 登先生
How does your head feel, mr. dunn?
为什么不放我走呢?
Why didn't you just let me go?
你不能死在这里
You're not dying here.
你在怕什么  谢博德医生  这么失控?
What are you so scared of, dr. shepherd, losing control?
颅内压稳定 继续神经检测
I.c.p.s are stable. continue neuro exams.
时刻注意血压
And keep an eye on his blood pressure.
-明早前让它降下去  -好的
I don't want it dropping overnight. sure.
潜意识里 也许你是知道的
Or maybe you know that, deep down,
你跟我半斤八两
You're no better than I am.
每时每刻都在决定人们的生死
You decide who lives and dies all the time,
但对你而言  叫做医疗
But for you, they call it medicine,
而不是人身侵犯
Not a capital offense.
大家都没得选择
Nobody gets to choose,
我没得选  医院的每个病人都没得选
Not me, not a patient in this hospital,
当然你屠杀的那五个女人也没得选
And certainly not the five women you slaughtered.
所以当我说你不能死在医院的时候
So when I say you're not gonna die in this hospital,
是在说 我绝对
I mean there is no way in hell
不能让你死在这家医院
I will let you die in this hospital.
想死没那么容易
You don't get off that easy.
我跟你是两种人
I am nothing like you.
梅丽迪斯  我在找德瑞克
Meredith, I was just looking for derek.
我以为他跟你在一起
I thought you'd be with him.
你看上去是个好人
You seem like a very nice person.
你很友善  你给了我一个机会
You've been very kind, and you've given me a chance.
似乎你想要去喜欢我
And it seems like you want to like me.
所以你应该有知情权
So it's only fair you should know...
红头绳和马尾辫
The pink and the ponytail
还有露齿笑?
And the smiling with the teeth?
我不得不说  都是假的
I'm a fraud. it's fake.
我不是那种妈妈们喜欢的女孩子
I'm not the kind of girl mothers like.
我并不快乐也不阳光
I'm not happy and bubbly.
我郁郁寡欢
I'm dark and cloudy,
因为我是那种不正常的甚至
Because I'm the type of crazy person who...
会为连环杀手感到伤心的人
Feels bad for serial killers.
很高兴见到你  梅丽迪斯
It was very nice to meet you, meredith.
怎么了?
What's wrong?
我想要见见你的母亲 伊兹
I want to meet your mother. iz.
我想要和你约会 丹尼
I want to go on a date with you, denny.
我要去餐馆吃饭
I want to... eat dinner at a restaurant
而不是像个疯子一样跟自己说话
And not look like a crazperson talking to myself.
我要和你手牵手
I want to walk down the street with you
漫步街头
And hold your hand.
我要把你介绍给我的朋友们   我想要
I want to tell my friends about you. I want...
我想要
I want...
什么?
What?
我想要你活着
I want you alive.
你是要跟我分手吗? 伊兹 斯蒂芬
Are you breaking up with me, izzie stevens?
我想是的
I think I am.
-要喝一杯吗?  -想  但是我有计划
You want to get a drink? I would, but I have plans.
好吧
Right.
高高得走路
Walk tall.
什么?
What?
你所能做的就是鼓足勇气走出来
All you can do is be brave enough to get out there.
你争取过  爱过
You fought. you loved.
你输过
You lost.
高高得走 托蕾斯
Walk tall, torres.
你迟到了  你真的迟到了
You're late. you're really late.
可能会吃闭门羹
They probably closed the kitchen.
我没有要放你鸽子
I didn't want you to think that I stood you up.
你喝醉了?
Are you drunk?
参军后  我整整五年
I haven't been on a date in a five years,
没有约会过  我
Since before I entered the military, and i--
我想要一个人静一下
I just wanted to take the edge off.
你喝醉了?  你迟到了  还喝醉了?
You're drunk? you're late and drunk?
我保证  我会补偿你的
I will make this up to you, I promise.
你不该被这样对待
This is not what you deserve.
我知道你不该被这样对待
I know this is not what you deserve,
我保证  我会补偿你
And I will make this up to you, i-i promise.
好吧 你别废话了  美好时光医生
Okay, before you say anything else, dr. good times,
你去洗个澡吧  你闻起来臭死了
You need to shower. you smell like a distillery.
不 不是这儿... 我
No. not here. i...
你爸爸  一直希望你把这个
Your father... always wanted you to have this
给一个值得托付的女孩
For the right girl.
显然爱迪不是
Addie wasn't right, clearly.
你和梅丽迪斯相处不超过1个小时
You spent less than an hour with meredith.
你几乎不了解她
You barely even know her.
已经足够了
I know enough.
我知道  对好人同情心是很正常的
I know... it's easier to have compassion
但对一个杀人犯却不是那么容易
For a good person than a murderer.
我知道你对于你父亲的事情
I know how angry you still are
仍然非常气愤
About what happened to dad.
我当然很气愤
Of course I'm angry.
你不是吗?
Aren't you?
在他的那边床位  我不能睡着
I still can't sleep on his side of the bed.
床垫都高低不平了
The mattress is wearing unevenly.
但是 不
But no...
我不生气 不再生气了
No, I'm not angry, not anymore.
宝贝
Sweetheart.
你眼中的世界黑白分明
You see things in black and white.
梅丽迪斯却不是
Meredith doesn't.
No.
你正需要这点
You need a spoonful of that.
你需要她的
You need her.
就是她了
She's the one.
杨!  杨!
Yang! yang!
我想起来了 我最好的手术
I thought of it. I thought of my best surgery ever.
你穿着鞋在我浴室洗澡
You're wearing shoes in my shower.
我第一次在战地处理爆炸损伤
My first blast injury in the field. uh-huh.
遍体鳞伤  是自制炸药害的
The body was mangled-- homemade explosive device,
电线铜片插入腹腔5英寸
Cooper and wires embedded 5 inches deep in the abdomen,
手脚仅靠一点皮肉挂在身上
Arms and legs hanging on by threads of skin.
我从没见过这种情形
I'd never seen anything like it,
书里没有  实习的时候也没有
Not in a textbook, not in residency.
难以置信  全身都是洞眼
Incredible, body full of holes--
伤科之梦
Trauma surgeon's dream.
在只要可以的地方放止血带
I put tourniquets on where I could,
赤手给动脉打结
Started tying off the arteries with my bare hands,
但到处都是血
But the bleeding was everywhere--
腹部  胸部
Stomach, chest.
能想到的最大压力就是我的身体
The best pressure I could think of was my own body,
所以我在他身上躺了足足两小时
So i-i laid there for two hours on top of him,
纹丝不动
Just not moving,
用我的手 膝盖 手肘
Trying to keep that dam from bursting
阻止血管爆裂
With my hands, my knees, my elbows.
全身是洞眼
Body full of holes,
却没有大量失血
And he never bled out.
我阻止了
I wouldn't let him.
他坚持到医院  一直到康复出院
He made it to the hospital, he made it home.
一个月后  他给我写了一封信
A month later, he... he sent me a letter
感谢我救了他
Thanking me for saving his life,
然后吞弹自尽
And then he shot himself.
那是我最成功的手术
That was my best surgery.
也是最失败的手术
And my worst.
我们是人
We're human.
所以就会犯错
We make mistakes.
我们犯错
We misestimate...
把它称之失误
We call it wrong.
但当外科医生作出不当判断
But when a surgeon makes a bad judgment call,
就复杂得多了
It's not as simple.
所以  我查了一下
So, uh, I checked,
接下来我们会有几天假期
And, uh, we have a few vacation days coming up.
去自驾游怎样?
Maybe we could take a road trip?
在爱荷华歇脚 看看玉米地?
Stop in iowa, see some corn?
你妈不是住在爱荷华么?
Doesn't your mom live in iowa?
我想她愿意见见你
Yeah. I think she'd like to meet you.
或者不要
Or not.
坏主意  别提了
Bad idea. forget it.
洗衣房有瓶龙舌兰酒
There's a bottle of tequila
上面写着我们的名字
In the laundry room that has our name on it.
别走开
Don't move.
爱历克斯
Alex...
我们得谈谈
We gotta talk.
人们受到伤害
People get hurt.
会流血
They bleed.
我很抱歉  我刚听说  现在怎样了?
I'm so sorry. I just heard. what happens now?
我们正在等待奇迹出现
Now we wait for a miracle.
每缝一针 我们都努力不已
So we struggle over every stitch.
每一处缝合
We agonize...
我们都痛苦不堪
Over every suture.
手术中 谢博德移除了一块头盖骨
During surgery, dr. shepherd removed a piece of your skull,
也就是说你的大脑
Which means your brain
现在只有硬脑膜盖着
Is now only covered by dura mater.
它事实上是裸露的
It's virtually exposed.
如果那块地方受到损伤
If somehow that area were to be damaged,
会引起颅内出血
It would cause intracranial bleeding,
意味着你的大脑会比今天
Which would cause your brain to swell
肿得更厉害
Worse than it did today,
也就意味着脑死亡
Which would result in brain death.
所以作为你的医生
So as your doctor,
我要你非常小心 别弄伤那个地方
I need you to be very careful not to damage it.
你明白我的意思吗?
Do you understand what I'm saying?
格蕾医生
Dr. grey...
你这么做
Are you doing this
是为了那个孩子还是为了我?
For the kid or for me?
因为迅雷不及掩耳的判断
Because the snap judgments,
它们来的很突然也很简单
The ones that come to us quickly and easily,
没有迟疑
Without hesitation...
只要能让你晚上安然入睡
Whatever helps you sleep at night.
将永远伴我们左右
They're the ones that haunt us forever.
Aah!